Dear Ms. Elsie,

I am writing to apply for an ICT Teacher (Part-time) position, personally informed by Mr. Agus Mastur Wahyudi - Art.

The opportunity informed seems exciting. I believe my years of technical experience and education will make me a suitable person for the position.

The main key strengths that I have, which I will contribute to this position include:

- I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Informatics Engineering as the baseline for an ICT Teacher.
- I have +7 years of experience in the IT industry as Software Developer / Engineer.

 Additionally, I have in-depth knowledge of the complete cycle of a software development project. Whenever the need arises, I learn new technologies.
- I like to teach and share my knowledge (through my <u>blog</u>) and be involved in teaching voluntary related technology both to kids and the elderly.

Attached is my CV/resume for your consideration. I can be reached on 08 5959 62 9090 / https://wa.me/085959629090

Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Gilang R. Aprianto



Profile

Web Developer with expertise in Ruby (on Rails) stacks with 7+ years. Passionate in sharing knowledge.

Employment History

Software Engineer at Mekari, Jakarta

July 2021 - Present

Bootstrapping digital signature product from scratch https://mekarisign.com and building early core engineering team

Web Developer at Upwork, Worldwide (remote)

July 2019 — June 2021

Make a living with a max 4-hour workday as a web developer, improve written & spoken English by working on an international team/project

Senior Software Engineer at MPM Group, Jakarta

July 2018 — July 2019

Ensure logistics and supply chain web applications perform excellence

Software Engineer at Karir Komunika Pratama, Yogyakarta

March 2016 — July 2018

Develop new features & maintenance web application Indonesian job portal: https://karir.com

Junior Web Developer at SoftwareSeni, Yogyakarta

September 2014 — February 2016

Working on Australian real estate web application.

Education

Sebelas Maret University, Surakarta

Major: Informatics Engineering B.Sc (GPA 3.35), in a concentration of Web Programming, System Analyst & Design

EF English First, Jakarta

Level: CERF B2 Intermediate, in concentration English for Adults

★ Teaching Related Experience

Lecturer Assistant

Become Lecturer Assistant (Asisten Dosen) on Computer Programming and RPL Subject, during collage on Sebelas Maret University

Volunteer

- Accompanying the elderly using technology (Google Doc, Blogging, etc)
- Teach kids how to use the camera & computer to become little journalist (during Jakarta coast Kelas Jurnalis Cilik)
- Mentoring neighborhood/friends /kids about Programming & Logic (self voluntary)

Details

Semarang Indonesia +62 8 5959 62 9090 gilangr.aprianto@gmail.com

Skills

Web Development

Blogging

Software Engineering

Programming

Database

Social Media

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

Hobbies

Technology, blogging, and street photography.

★ Links

Blog: Authored gizipp.com for additional information, writing, and projects.

Github: https://github.com/gizipp

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/gizipp

Portfolio

- For recent personal projects: gizipp.com/portfolio/#personal
- For recent professional projects: gizipp.com/portfolio/#professional
- For open source contribution: My OSS Contribution

GIZ! Tools

Publicized tools.gizipp.com: internet and web tools, e.g DNS checker, template converter, WHOIS tools, etc

This .PDF resume also available in .HTML and .TXT format.